MICAH KIRKPATRICK

micah@kirkpatrickcore.com

Skills Summary

Experienced Director & Chief Data Scientist with a demonstrated history of working in the public safety and finance industry. Skilled in Data Science and leading Analytics and Engineering teams. Have Developed and Integrated CI/CD/CML systems.

Experience

iParametrics

Director & Chief Data Scientist / October, 2018 – Present

- Architected, lead and built the companies CI/CD/CML system from experimentation to training and deployment of machine learning algorithms to internal and external company clients
- Developed predictive algorithms and lead Analytics & Engineering team for developing machine learning technology solutions for FEMA disaster recovery operations, disaster spending, weather tracking
- Developed proprietary deep learning algorithms for company clients to predict specific KPIs regarding military special operations
- Developed and implemented a machine learning system for Salesforce to predict their global risk regarding the health and safety of their global operations and general workforce
- Heavily involved with data mining and feature engineering for geospatial purposes involving LiDAR point-cloud data and other integral data relative to predictive modeling automation process

Bank of America Merrill Lynch

Data Scientist / December 2016 – September 2018

- Developed machine learning models for advanced equity options strategies
- Developed machine learning algorithms to predict various economic KPIs
- Developed machine learning algorithms and processes for AI portfolio prediction and optimization

US Army Corps of Engineers

Senior Economist / August 2012 – November 2016

• Lead junior Economists, Geospatial and Computer Engineers to develop innovative systems for predicting engineering information and economic indicators integral to USACE operations

Economist / September 2010 – July 2012

- Developed machine learning algorithms for various USACE operations and studies
- Selected to innovate and successfully proved data science / machine learning approaches and systems development in USACE operations

United States Marine Corps

Aircrew Chief / October 2005 – September 2010

• Deployed in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom

Education

Degree / Date of Graduation

- Georgia Institute of Technology: MBA Management of Technology 2016 to 2017
- Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications: Global Business 2017
- Suffolk University: MS International Economics 2012
- Suffolk University: BS Economics, Mathematics 2010 to 2012
 - o Magna Cum Laude
 - o Inductee of *The International Honor Society In Economics* **OAE**
 - o Recipient of the Academic Achievement Award in Economics